这是二零二二年普通高等学校招生全国统一考试英语科听力部分。该部分分为第一、第二两节。注意。回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。现在是听力试音时间。
Oh, hello. I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to
find out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
Uh, what kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes. Every day except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages.
You know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish. Tuesday, Italian.
Wednesday, German. And Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
Okay. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。听力考试正式开始。请看听力部分第一节。第一节，听下面五段对话。每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
three A, B, and Read
三个选项中，选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话仅。引读一遍。例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。你将听到以下内容。
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案标在试卷上。衬衫的价格为九八。放十五遍是，所以你选择
option to Jenny, you can just drop me here.
项，并将其标在试卷上。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容。
But we're two streets away from the office.
It's fine. I had a big breakfast and feel like a bit of walk.
Hello, George. You look tired.
Didn't sleep well last night?
No, not at all.
I had to work flat out to meet the project deadline.
Now I'm really feeling a bit run down.
John, can't we go someplace and talk?
It's so noisy in here.
Well, there's a small park across the street.
It's usually not crowded at this time of day.
We've got to do something about the neighbor's dog.
Why? Has he been into your flower garden again?
The flower garden, the garbage can, and yesterday he started digging holes in the
yard. Hello, we have a reservation in the name of Mr.
Jones. Is there any table by the window?
Sorry, we've got this corner table for you.
It's quiet here, not close to the door.
The After three A, B, and
第一节到此结束。第二节，听下面五段对话或独白，每段对话或独白后。有几个小题。从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题。每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Dave, don't forget, we are invited out to dinner tonight.
Oh, yeah, I almost forgot.
What time? Seven thirty.
We should leave the house by six thirty.
You know how bad the traffic is that time of night.
It's informal, isn't it?
Yeah, you can wear your new sports jacket, the one I got you as an anniversary gift.
Okay, well, I've got to go.
I'll try to get home a little earlier today.
Good. Dave, don't forget, we are invited out to dinner tonight.
Oh, yeah, I almost forgot.
What time? Seven thirty.
We should leave the house by six thirty.
You know how bad the traffic is that time of night.
It's informal, isn't it?
Yeah, you can wear your new sports jacket, the one I got you as an anniversary gift.
Okay, well, I've got to go.
I'll try to get home a little earlier today.
Good. We need to decide exactly when we're going to move.
听下面一段对话，回答第八和第九两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间。
Any suggestions? I think July would be the best time.
Our sales are always down that month.
We could move all the office equipment at a weekend.
Do everything at once.
I think a weekend's too short.
Maybe we should do it department by department.
What do you mean?
Well, each week a different department would move.
That way, there would always be people here to handle customer inquiries, phone
calls, and so on.
Hmm, that's a good idea.
We need to decide exactly when we're going to move.
Any suggestions? I think July would be the best time.
Our sales are always down that month.
We could move all the office equipment at a weekend.
Do everything at once.
I think a weekend's too short.
Maybe we should do it department by department.
What do you mean?
Well, each week a different department would move.
That way, there would always be people here to handle customer inquiries, phone
calls, and so on.
Hmm, that's a good idea.
听下面一段对话，回答第十至第十二三个小题。现在你有十。十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题
So, Mr. Peter Sells, I'd be curious to know what were the early connections in your
life that led you into the art field?
My grandfather was an art dealer in Munich.
They had a great museum in Munich.
He took me to the museum, and I responded very strongly to what I saw on the walls
there. I learned about art from him.
I learned about looking at art from him.
I think that's what really got me started.
Then, many years later, after I got out of the army, I went to study art history at
the University of Chicago.
Tell us more about your experiences of looking at art with your grandfather.
Well, we looked at the famous paintings by the great artists like Rembrandt,
Botticelli, and Albrecht Dürer.
Ruben's paintings were my favorites.
Yes, I remember these things.
This was when I was between 10 and 15.
When I was 14, I was so anxious to see more art that a friend of mine and I bicycled
across the Alps to see Venice.
That was a big adventure.
So, Mr. Peter Sells,
I'd be curious to know what were the early connections in your life that led you
into the art field?
My grandfather was an art dealer in Munich.
They had a great museum in Munich.
He took me to the museum and I responded very strongly to what I saw on the walls
there. I think that's what really got me started.
Then, many years later, after I got out of the army,
I went to study art history at the University of Chicago.
Tell us more about your experiences of looking at art with your grandfather.
Well, we looked at the famous paintings by the great artists like Rembrandt,
Botticelli, and Albrecht Dürer.
Ruben's paintings were my favorites.
Yes, I remember these things.
This was when I was between 10 and 15.
When I was 14, I was so anxious to see more art that a friend of mine and I bicycled
across the Alps to see Venice.
That was a big adventure.
听下面一段对话，回答第十三至第十六四个小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
Hi, John. Haven't seen you for ages.
Hi, Susan. Fancy meeting you here on the train.
How is your college life?
What can I say?
I've survived. What happened?
Well, early last March, I started doing a part -time job in a law firm.
A few weeks before, I had started writing my term paper.
I thought I could finish it by August.
That was a pretty good idea, trying to have some work experience.
For the first three weeks, you know, I tried.
I got up early and worked for an hour on my paper before going to work.
But work was so fun.
I met tons of new people, and soon I couldn't find even a minute for my paper.
So I had to quit my part -time job and finally finished my paper in October.
Well, it's never too late to mend.
It's kind of hard to find a between what you have to do and what you want to do.
Yeah, it's really important for me to balance study and work.
And I think I should learn to exercise some self -control.
Hi, John. Haven't seen you for ages.
Hi, Susan. Fancy meeting you here on the train.
How is your college life?
What can I say?
I've survived. What happened?
Well, early last March, I started doing a part -time job in a law firm.
A few weeks before, I had started writing my term paper.
I thought I could finish it by August.
That was a pretty good idea, trying to have some work experience.
For the first three weeks, you know, I tried.
I got up early and worked for an hour on my paper before going to work.
But work was so fun.
I met tons of new people, and soon I couldn't find even a minute for my paper.
So I had to quit my part -time job and finally finished my paper in October.
Well, it's never too late to mend.
It's kind of hard to find a between what you have to do and what you want to do.
Yeah, it's really important for me to balance study and work.
And I think I should learn to exercise some self -control.
听下面一段独白，回答第十七至第二十四个小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
Being an athlete is very fun, painful, and exciting.
Every time I come to the track, I feel like I'm out of this place.
This is Botswana National Stadium.
This is where I train.
When I saw Usain Bolt running in 2012 London Olympics, I was amazed.
Just watching him run got me motivated.
I quit being a chess player and started to run.
I went to the 2016 Olympics and went to the finals at the age of 18, and wow, I
finished fifth. It was a dream come true to me, but I still wanted more.
The training is super hard, but the hardest part for me is that I got an injury, an
injury which may take me out for years.
For a period of time, as a young athlete, I didn't know what to do.
I lost focus, but now I'm back on the track.
I really want to be there at the Olympics and do what I did before, do much, much
greater. I don't care about the gold.
I don't care about the silver.
I want to do my best, you know?
Take everything and show it to the world.
Being an athlete is very fun, painful, and exciting.
Every time I come to the track, I feel like I'm out of this place.
This is Botswana National Stadium.
This is where I train.
When I saw Usain Bolt running in 2012 London Olympics, I was amazed.
Just watching him run got me motivated.
I quit being a chess player and started to run.
I went to the 2016 Olympics and went to the finals at the age of 18, and wow, I
finished fifth. It was a dream come true to me, but I still wanted more.
The training is super hard, but the hardest part for me is that I got an injury, an
injury which may take me out for years.
For a period of time, as a young athlete, I didn't know what to do.
I lost focus, but now I'm back on the track.
I really want to be there at the Olympics and do what I did before, do much, much
greater. I don't care about the gold.
I don't care about the silver.
I want to do my best, you know?
Take everything and show it to the world.
第二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案
on Thank you for watching.
转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
听力部分到此结束。
you.